Abdulrahman M. Alanazi

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

iabdulrahman.91@gmail.com

+966 580627922

linkedin.com/in/abdulrahmanalanazi

https://www.iabdul.tech/#/

Summary

4 years of Software Engineering experience, with 2 years in DevOps Engineering

Experienced Full-stack Software Engineer trained in Laravel PHP, Flutter, SwiftUI, VueJS, ReactJS, Android, FastAPI, Angular, MLFlow, Jenkins, Github Action, Git, Gitlab CI/CD pipelines, Terraform, Docker, and Kubernetes.

Enhanced QA by adding more than 450 automated test cases (TDD).

Drove MLOps / DevOps to automate Machine Learning Model Development life cycle in National Center for Artificial Intelligence (SDAIA-NCAI).

Built Machine Learning Development Platform Infrastructure on Huawei Cloud using Infrastructure as Code.

Experience



Machine Learning DevOps Engineer

سدایا | SDAIA

Aug 2021 - Present (7 months +)

- Deployed Self-managed instance of GitLab on-premise
- Provision ML infrastructure using Terraform on Huawei Cloud.
- Developed Machine Learning CI/CD pipeline.
- Built Kubernetes Cluster and setup various environment.
- Built Docker Images for different R&D needs such as FastAPI
- Accelerate MLOps by Dynamically allocating GPUs and HPCs.
- Built Code (Git) and Data (DVC) Repositories for National Center for Artificial Intelligence.



Full-stack Developer

سدایا | SDAIA

Jun 2021 - Present (9 months +)

- Developed AI Oasis Website using Laravel PHP
- Developed IOS and Android app for Arabic Speech Recognition (ASR) using VueJS
- Developed MacOS and Windows Desktop Client Application using Flutter framework.

Senior Software Engineer

Tamkeen Technologies

Jun 2020 - Jun 2021 (1 year 1 month)

- Built 'Morajea | مُراجع' application using Laravel PHP, ReactJS, React Native
- Enhance Product quality by established TDD using PHPUnit
- Automate QA by introducing testing stages to building pipeline using Jenkins
- Improve CI by containerizing Dev environment using Docker.
- Documented API contracts to escalate collaboration between developers.
- Increase Agility by applying Agile -Scrum principles and practices.



Teaching Assistance | Grader

DePaul University College of Computing and Digital Media

Jan 2018 - Oct 2019 (1 year 10 months)

- Experienced grader for many CS, SE, and IT courses.
- Weekly grading 30+ students' code, solutions and algorithms.
- Graded eight 2xx, 3xx, 4xx courses levels.

IT Technician

SABIC

Mar 2013 - Aug 2013 (6 months)

Responsibilities:

- End-user helpdesk.
- Microsoft Windows 7 Deployment.
- Hardware Troubleshooting.

Education



DePaul University

Master's degree, Computer Software Engineering

2018 - 2019

Degree Honors: with Distinction Major: Software Engineering

Concentration: Software Development.

DePaul University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science

2015 - Jun 2018

Degree Honors: Magna Cum Laude.

Major: Computer Science.

Concentration: Software Engineering. Dean's List for 8 academic quarters.

Jubail Industrial College

Associate's Degree, Information Technology 2010 - 2013

Licenses & Certifications



Machine Learning DevOps Engineer - Udacity

Skills

Machine Learning DevOps • DevOps • Kubernetes • Terraform • Docker • DVC • agile • Python (Programming Language) • Service-Oriented Architecture (SOA) • Architecture